So, I spent all day playing around with
Opus 5.5 and GBD6 Astra, and I just put
them head-to-head on 12 real use cases.
I'm talking things like building
websites or editing videos and Instagram
reels, planning trip itineraries,
creating real professional branded
deliverables like slide decks and
spreadsheets and analytics and P&Ls,
also creating real worlds like 3D
playable games, or 3D experiences to
help you actually learn new concepts.
We'll also look into browser use and
things like creating carousels. And on
all 12 of these experiments, I will show
you how long it took each model to run
and how much it cost each time. So, I
don't want to waste any time. Let's just
get straight into this one. Okay, so
last night I made this type of
comparison video between Opus 5.5 and
GBD6 Soul. Today, we're doing it with
GBD6 Astra. In this video, I'm using
both of these models, Opus and Astra on
high effort. And I'm using these inside
of my subscriptions, but I'm going to
tell you how much this would have cost
as if it was API billing, just so we can
get a better I don't know, we can
contextualize it a little bit better
because I don't know if you're on a 20
bucks a month plan or 200. So this is
the API billing for Opus 5.5 and GBD6
Astra. What's really interesting is that
Astra is 2.5 times more expensive than
Opus 5.5. So is it going to perform 2.5
times better than Opus 5.5? That's what
we're going to see. So in all these
experiments, I'm basically shooting off
the exact same prompts to both models in
their respective harnesses and then
we're going to judge the results. Now,
as far as my video yesterday, I did make
a mistake and I had two of those
experiments. The agents kind of like
worked together, so I made sure that
didn't happen this time. What I
obviously should have been doing there
is what I normally do when I run these
test videos is I put them in different
work trees so they literally can't
touch. So, sorry about that guys. I
apologize. I hope the video was still
insightful. Yesterday, I had a million
things going on and I was honestly
really tired at the point of filming,
but I wanted to get it out as soon as
possible. So, sorry about that. But,
let's get into today's comparison. So,
if you watched yesterday's video, then
you're going to recognize some of these
experiments with Opus 5.5, but I decided
to also run those exact same ones with
Astra because I thought they were really
good use cases and things that I would
actually do with these models. So this
one is Opus 5.5 with perk form. Same
prompt, same brand guidelines as you can
see. I like how it put the keys and the
can on different layers than the
background. As we scroll, we get some
text coming in. We come down here to an
AI generated image that it made. Coffee
in one hand, protein in the other. We
can see that we get the scroll effect of
the text right here. It's very simple. I
don't like how this ore is so tiny. That
definitely could have been bigger. I
really like this effect where you're
pulling the tab and you're getting this
basically animated. I think it created a
video from this, but it's really trying
to piece this all together and tell a
story here. I like the images here. I
like the drop shadow. I like how the
text is coming in as we scroll. I really
like this animation where these are sort
of like rotating into, you know, the
front view. And then that's basically
FAQ last animation right here. And then
that's the end of this page. And here is
Astra's attempt at this same site. You
can see similar style, similar feel, but
obviously a little bit different. I like
the big text in the back that says one.
I think that was a nice touch. We have
some layering going on here as well.
We'll continue to scroll down. We have
text sort of coming in, but not the
exact same way that it happens in the
Opus version. I like how these two
things sort of merge into one. I think
this could be cleaned up. It's not super
smooth. I like the vision, but it could
have definitely been done better. Now, I
really like this view. We're getting
these different flavors here and we can
switch between this. This feels very I
don't know. This feels premium. It feels
very clean. It doesn't feel AI generated
here. And I like how the colors changing
in the background over here. I think
this is really nice. We also have a
large ice cube and some coffee coming in
right here. FAQ. And then we come down
to basically the end of the site. Now,
to be honest, I think overall I enjoyed
the experience more on the Opus site. It
just felt a little bit more premium to
me. I also just kind of prefer the dark
mode typically, and this was kind of
like it felt more like this one
consistent bright throughout. I mean,
that's obviously not true, but I liked
the overall vibe of this one better,
especially the hero section. The hero
section here is like the first
impression, and this looks a little bit
cheaper. So, as far as um quality, I'm
going to give this one to Opus. But if
we take a look at the actual pricing,
here's what we got. So, Opus was 40
minutes, whereas Astra was 32 minutes,
and Opus was $18 bucks.32 and Astra was
$11.33.
So, it's very interesting to me, and I
want to see if this is consistent
throughout. Astra is a 2.5 times more
expensive model, but in this case, it
was faster and cheaper. Ultimately, I'm
still going to give this round to Opus
5.5. I think when it comes to creativity
and design and some of this like visual
judgment, I think that Opus has Astrobe
in most cases, but we will see if that
holds true throughout the rest of the
experiment. So, so far, Opus is up one
to zero. And real quick, guys, both of
the sites that you just saw, as well as
a ton of other sites that I actually
have live, used this completely free
skill that you guys can go grab right
now. The link for this will be down in
the description, and it has all of these
skills and prompts and ideas about
building good websites inside of it. So,
go grab that for free. Let's get back to
the video. So, moving on here to number
two. You guys know this is a use case
that I love. I think it's a really good
benchmark. It shows what the models are
really capable of. I gave them both this
folder that has 105 gigabytes of
recordings from our last event, AIS
Live. And I basically said, "Hey, I want
you to go through this, create me a 30
second sizzle reel that we can use to
market our next event in October,
October 17th and 18th. And I wanted to
edit all this with hyperframes." So,
let's go ahead and give both of these
videos a watch. We'll do Opus 5.5 first
and then Astra. Hello. Hello, AIS live.
My
>> Oh my god, I'm so excited for this.
>> Let's Let's get some energy going in
here.
>> It's been a great two days.
I think this is so so good. You guys saw
this exact same version yesterday if you
watched my comparison yesterday. But I
think it's incredible. I mean, I think
one thing that we don't even call out
enough is how good it was at sinking to
the beats of the music. This scene, for
example, it was going bump and
everything was coming in with the music.
It was super energetic. There was a lot
of layering and depth. Like it wasn't
just, hey, here's a recording and here's
some text. It was like, "Hey, let's put
a recording in the background and then
overlay another recording on top with
the drop shadow and we have like an
overlay and we have the opacity turned
down." Like, I think that this was a
really, really well done video. And here
we have Ash's version. Let's go ahead
and give it a watch. Let's get you guys
paid. Right
now, we're up to $32,000 with them.
one workspace, my entire agency, a small
folder on my desktop.
Okay, so not nearly as good. The
beginning felt awkward. It was very
quiet. The music was very like slow and
it also didn't feel like it came in
until maybe 5 seconds in. I think Asha
does a really good job with vision and
screenshotting things and putting in
B-roll. That makes sense, but the energy
was not there. The creativity was not
there at all. Like I said, in general,
it feels to me like Opus and Claude
models are just way more creative and
have better, I don't know, taste in a
lot of ways. And yeah, let's take a look
at the pricing of this one. Opus ran for
31 minutes and cost 10 bucks, whereas
Astra ran for 39 minutes and $21, almost
22. So I think across the board, Opus
wins here. It was faster, cheaper, and
the output was better. So, we've got
Opus 5.5 coming in so far at up 2 and 0
or 2 to zero against Astra. Let's move
on to number three. So, for number
three, I gave them this recording of
myself and I told them to make an
Instagram reel for me, which is using
hyperframes. And there's also a skill in
my student kit that basically helps them
um create these Instagram reels. So,
they're given pretty much the same
stuff, but the outputs are very
different. So, let's take a look at GBD6
Astra. Stop prompting Claude. Andre
Karpathy thinks there's a much better
way to work with AI. And his method has
three layers. Layer one is the spec.
Instead of giving Claude a task and
hoping it understands you, work with it
to create a detailed spec first. Have
Claude interview you about what you're
actually trying to achieve, then break
the work into smaller checkpoints before
it starts. Layer two is the verifier.
Before Claude does anything, define
exactly what a good result looks like.
Then give it ways to actually check its
own work, whether that's another AI
model or real data or tests that it can
run on its own. And layer three is the
environment. Build a workspace where
Claude already has your instructions,
your knowledge, your skills, and your
rules every single time you use it. So
instead of becoming better at writing
prompts, you're building an entire
system around Claude that makes it
better every time you use it. All right,
so that was Ashstro. Let's take a look
at Opus' output. Stop prompting Claude.
Andre Karpathy thinks there's a much
better way to work with AI. And his
method has three layers. Layer one is
the spec. Instead of giving Claude a
task and hoping it understands you, work
with it to create a detailed spec first.
Have Claude interview you about what
you're actually trying to achieve. Then
break the work into smaller checkpoints
before it starts. Layer two is the
verifier. Before Cloud does anything,
define exactly what a good result looks
like. Then give it ways to actually
check its own work, whether that's
another AI model or real data or tests
that it can run on its own. And layer
three is the environment. Build a
workspace where Claude already has your
instructions, your knowledge, your
skills, and your rules every single time
you use it. So instead of becoming
better at writing prompts, you're
building an entire system around Claude
that makes it better every time you use
it. So just ask yourself, which one of
those was easier to watch? Which one
felt quicker? I think Opus's felt way
better. It was more engaging. I think
some of the sound effects were a little
bit too much, but it was way more
engaging. There was more going on. The
B-roll was more interesting. The
animations were more interesting. I just
think that this one was a much better
output. GPT
Astros just felt bland, you know? It
just felt very vanilla, very mundane. I
don't know. It it it wasn't very
creative. And what I think is really
weird about this is as I've been using
Astra more since Opus dropped and since
Soul dropped, Astra feels like it went
down. It feels like it downgraded.
You'll see later I have some other
experiments where I was like Astra
usually does this better, but it feels
like Astra got worse because I actually
made a video of me editing with Astra
and it was really really good. And since
then the Astra editing outputs have like
definitely degraded. So I'm not sure
what's going on there. But as far as
this specific experiment, Astra ran for
about half the time that Opus ran and
cost $2 less. So about N bucks compared
to 11 bucks. And overall, the output
here is going to go to Opus 5.5. I mean,
Opus 5.5 is a very, very impressive
model to me so far, especially when it
comes to creative taste and judgment and
things like that, vision. I know these
first three experiments were definitely
more on this design side, but we're
going to get into some other
experiments. So, let's move on to number
four. Okay, so in this one I gave Astra
a ton of data, ton of mock data, and I
told it to build me an investor deck, a
financial report, an analytics
dashboard, and a client landing page. So
pretty big request. And one of the
things you'll notice here is that Astra
asked me a question in the middle of
this goal because I did slash goal
prompts for all these. Now, Codeex in
general, I think it's a harness thing,
is way better than Cloud Code at asking
you questions, and it will keep the goal
going in case you don't answer, but it
asks me way more questions, which I
really like because it helps me make
sure that the outputs I'm getting are
more tailored towards me. So, anyways,
let's real quick go through Astra's
deliverables to me. The first one we
have is an investor deck with 17 slides.
We can see that it generated some Bright
Path branding up here. It generated this
little image. We have some big hero
stats right here. The slides are very
simple. There's not too much going on.
Um, I think that they're these could
look a little more professional if there
were like lines and sort of some
boundaries between, but overall, they're
not too wordy. They're pretty clean.
They're also just very simple. It
definitely used a Google sheet on the
back to generate these visualizations,
but there's nothing too impressive about
this. I mean, I think it did a good job
going through the corpus of information
I gave it on the mock company data. But
besides that, it probably could have
leveraged, you know, more images a
little bit better or probably could have
had a logo to make this feel more
branded. Nothing too crazy, but it
definitely did a decent job. We'll open
up the Google Sheet financial report. We
have some topline metrics over here as
well as um some charts to go with it,
some visualizations of the data. It's a
big summary. We've got some assumptions
here. Um we have a cash plan, we have
P&L, we've got revenue. I mean, it's
formatted nicely. It's branded. And I'm
not sure if this stuff has formulas in
here that would change. It looks like
some of these have some very basic
formulas going on with like some sums
and things of that nature, but not all
the sheets do or not all the cells.
Sorry. These ones are just very basic
sums. Um, marketing people and checks.
Okay. So, nothing too crazy like I think
that this style of output could have
been generated with, you know, GBD516
soul or even Luna. That's a very simple
output. Anyways, let's take a look at
the analytics dashboard. We'll just look
at this right here in the Codeex desktop
app. We have um this is pretty much
exactly what I expected Astra to design.
It always kind of looks like this. It's
not terrible, but it just looks very
very simple. We have recurring revenue
here. Can we switch between these? No.
We can switch between the dates. Q1, Q2.
We can see other stats down here. What
are these on the side? We have sales
pipeline. Okay, this has some filtering
for us as well. We've got the customer
health. We've got the What is this?
acquisition efficiency. We have
financial performance. And then we also
have um execution tracker and some other
data notes down here. Okay, nothing too
crazy. And then finally, we'll open up
the client landing page. Actually, I'll
just open this up in the actual browser
here. So, make your next move a clear
one. Bright path. We have the nice
little logo behind. I like how this is
on an angle. Not too bad. Let's keep on
scrolling here. Number comes up.
Actually, that's interesting. Only the
412 was an animated number. If you watch
this, I don't know why I didn't do that
with these numbers as well. I will
deduct one point for that. This number
came in nice. We have this little
dashboard. I do like this element. I
think this feels pretty professional.
And as we keep scrolling down, we have
some pricing. We have FAQ. Okay, so
that's basically it. Nothing too crazy
at all. I don't know. I feel like it
could have maybe leveraged using some
image generation a little bit more and
done a little bit more, but it's not too
too bad. Let's head over to Claude and
see what we got from Opus 5.5. Okay,
same exact thing over here. Here we're
getting a little bit of a sneak peek to
the landing page, which looks like it
could be cooler. It's kind of weird
because of the desktop app view, but
anyways, let's start with the investor
deck. I'm going to just keep this in
here. Um, see what is happening. Know
what to do next. So, I like how there's
an image in the back. I don't know. It
just feels pretty cool. Growing service
businesses still run on spreadsheets. We
have an image right there. One view of
the See, this is what I meant. Like,
Opus is putting at least some lines and
it's just giving it a little more depth
than what Astra did earlier. Astra also
chose to connect right to Google Sheets
and just build it in there. whereas Opus
did this in a just a PowerPoint, but
we've got some images here to go along
with these stats. I think that this
slide looks pretty good. We've got a
table there. We've got some other stats,
more tables, more charts here, different
colors. It's kind of emphasizing these
three. Got a little bit of a churn
versus new visibility to
recommendations. 68 people. Okay, this
would be filled in with actual numbers
for what we're trying to see. This is
where Astra asked me what numbers we
wanted to put here. Oh, I can actually
edit move this in here. I didn't even
know that. But Astra asked me what I
wanted to put for these these metrics.
Whereas Opus didn't even say, "Hey, do
you want me to make these up or do you
have these metrics?" Astra stopped and
asked me that. But anyways, as far as
the design of this one, I like the
design here a little bit better. Let's
see what else we've got. We will go to
the 12 tab financial report on
analytics. This one's definitely more
verbose. You can tell right away this
one feels more like an analysis compared
to just having a spreadsheet. But as we
go through unit economics, cash and
runway forecast, they feel very similar.
Like there's nothing too crazy except
for this one. This is something I do
want to call out. This sheet has way
more references, more references, more
formulas. And I do think that's a huge
deal. Like having a sheet by be dynamic
where I can change the numbers and see
what actually changes is definitely a an
important factor, right? like you don't
want to just have a static sheet that
you would have to have one of your
agents regenerate every time you wanted
to change some numbers. So I think the
fact that they do look sort of similar.
I mean Opus is using more like colors
and stuff in here but Opus has more
formulas and I think that that is a big
deal when you're creating spreadsheets.
The analytics dashboard as far as a
design doesn't look anything too much
better than what we saw from uh Codex,
what we saw from Astra. They're very
very similar. We've got revenue, we've
got customers, we can go on light mode,
dark mode. We can do different quarters,
and we can see some other sort of
analysis here. I would say that nothing
about either of the dashboards was too
like stand out compared to the other.
And then we'll go ahead and look at this
landing page that I built. Okay, so you
can see that this is a clawed artifact.
See what is happening, know what to do
next. We have a little bit of a dynamic
image in the background. Okay, so we
start to scroll in. We can click into
these things or no, no. Okay, these are
just showing us what's going on. Six
locations. Your numbers live where the
work happens, wherever the work happens.
We have some different pictures here.
We're definitely getting more of a story
being told here compared to I don't like
how this is right aligned. That seems a
little bit odd. Don't love that. We have
this dashboard where as we scroll, we're
seeing numbers move along. So, I really
like that element. We have more text,
more numbers coming in down here. Got a
quote, an image, different pricing. We
can see how this would scale up. Okay,
that's not too bad. Overall, Opus is
definitely doing a better job with the
design because it's not just the design.
It's also it just feels more like it's
telling a story. Now, of course, some of
the quality judging I'm doing here is
very subjective. Like, some of you guys
might have way preferred Astra's
website. Some of you guys probably
prefer this one. So, it's hard to say
like subjectively, but when we look at
the actual cost, you can't argue with
the numbers. Opus came in here about 7
minutes, 6 minutes faster. 7 minutes
faster, as well as only about a dollar
more expensive. So, I would pay the
extra dollar here to get the outputs
that we got here from Opus. And this is
just crazy. I was not expecting this to
be, you know, so heavily in Opus' favor,
but not only from the design. There were
way more formulas inside of the sheet
with Opus. So, anyways, let us move on
to the next one. Okay, so this one is a
game. I had them generate this game for
me where we're sort of like trapped in a
museum. I'll actually show you. I said
to build a polished browser game where
the player escapes a miniature museum
after closing. include three connected
rooms, an inventory, five link puzzles,
contextual hints, sound controls, a
complete ending. I'll be judging you on
creativity, realism, lighting, design,
the entire experience around the game
itself. So, let's hop back into this
tab. This is what we got from Opus 5.5.
I'm just going to say begin again. And
what I like about this is, let me unmute
this tab. You can see that it basically
like runs us through a story. So,
there's music playing
and it's sort of setting the scene. You
were only meant to sit down for a minute
and now it looks like you got stuck
inside the museum. I don't know if like
I wasn't reading that. So, I don't know
if like we fell asleep and then they
closed and now we have to escape or
something, but the lights are off. The
whole place is dark except for
that moonlight. Okay. So, I can walk
around like this. I can control my
mouse.
As far as like the the graphics of this
are not too bad, especially when you
consider how long it it ran for. You can
see like there's glare. I'm not
necessarily going to like play this full
game and figure out how to escape, but
it's not too bad. I mean, it's obviously
a decent experience. The one thing I'd
say is my mouse is doing that thing
again where it's not like locked in.
Meaning, if I move my mouse out of frame
then, oh, I can still control it. So,
I'm I have to hold to look around
though. So, it's a little bit weird, but
I'm still my mouse isn't in frame at all
and it's working. Anyways, this is not
too bad of an output at I like the
flashlight as well. I can examine things
like stopped at 10:47 the minute I got
locked in. The pendulum hangs dead
still.
So yeah, it's kind of like an escape
room. You just have to find find clues,
try to figure out how you can find
things to help you get out of this room.
I can't see anything at all here.
I can read this little piece. We can see
this locked at 10:47. So I'm not doing a
very good job at actually like figuring
out what to do to escape. But so far, I
mean, the the graphics and the realism,
not too bad at all. I like it. Okay, so
here is Ash's version. It's called The
Last Curator. The doors close at 9. You
stay a little too long. Let's step
inside. So, this is not as immersive
right away. This is more like a It feels
more like a puzzle that I'm looking at
rather than I'm inside. But we can see
we can click into different things. We
can try to access a code to open up the
cabinet. We can click into the clock.
Something is missing. The mechanism
needs the winding key, the brass
nighting gale. I sing when the sea, the
sky, and the hours agree. Okay, a bit of
a riddle there for me to figure out. We
have, "If you were still here at 9,
don't force the door. Restore the
closing ritual. Begin with the
collection cabinet. Our oldest treasures
always come first. Count their gold
marks." We have eight dots, three dots,
five dots. Let's see if I can open the
cabinet with that. What did I say? 853.
Open the cabinet. Not quite. The
mechanism settles back into silence.
Your clues are safe in the journal. Oh,
wait. I didn't do those in order. So, it
would be 3 85. Let's try that.
Okay, there we go. I got that open. Now
I can read the keeper tide table. So,
anyways, I think you guys get the point.
They had to think about the story here,
how you make a puzzle, how you make
something where you can sort of like
work your way through it. But I gave
them such a vague prompt that Astra
decided to make it more of this
experience and Opus decided to make it
more of a realistic immersive like 3D
game experience. And that's why I say
this is so subjective. It's hard to tell
because if I gave them a very very
specific prompt and I wanted, you know,
I had a vision of what I wanted, then
that's a bit different story. But in
this case, I didn't really know the
vision I wanted. So let's take a look at
what the actual cost was here. Astra ran
for 34 minutes and Opus ran for an hour
and a half and Astra took about $8 where
Opus took $31. Now, this one's really
tough because like I said, if I would
have given more specific and I had a
vision, then I'd be able to assess which
one I liked more. And I think as far as
like getting into an environment and
being able to start playing it right
away and not being overwhelmed, I would
say that I'm going to give this one to
Astra and it came back very quick. It
wasn't very expensive and it lets me
sort of iterate on top of it and, you
know, figure out what I do want. But I
still do appreciate the level of quality
that Opus created and the the vision it
had. I guess the immersive experience
that it created for me. I think that
like I said, both very very impressive
results. But you also take a look at
this. And I'm going to give this one to
Astra. Okay, so this one was
interesting. I gave them or I told them
to go get a hundred of my recent YouTube
videos and create different concepts and
make it a 3D world that I could explore
in order to learn these concepts. So
here is Astra's version. We have this
little 3D world to explore. Astra
decided to make this a a first person
sort of game. You can see that. Oops, it
just opened up my clawed one. Sorry
about that. So, we can see we have
tools, we have context, we have prompts,
we have useful projects, trust and
safety. So, let's just go into something
like we'll go into models real quick and
see what's in here for us to play. We're
able to come in here and explore this
room. I click F. We can see different
experiments that we could run. Let's do
one small to run experiment. Okay, so
experiment complete. check your
understanding to earn a stamp. Okay, so
it's kind of gified where you have to
take a little quiz or something in order
to get a stamp and then I think the idea
is that you try to get all of the
stamps. So anyway, let's see what other
sorts of experiments we have. I'll go
into the skills area real quick. Touch
an idea, see what happens. Okay, how do
I touch an idea? I has experiment,
discover, sources, check. Okay, so the
check is like where you check your
knowledge. Okay, cool. Um, build check.
I'm not exactly sure. Make a reusable
recipe that plans, builds, and checks.
Okay, so plan, build, check. Run
experiment. Is that what I do?
No, it says plan, plan, check. Plan,
build, check. Okay, there we go. Um, I
don't know. I don't exactly understand
what's going on. Like the experience of
this is a little bit overwhelming. I
thought that this would be easier to
understand. Let's see what happens here.
You want to help Pip cross a broken
bridge, inspect it, repair what's
missing, then test the repair. Okay, so
inspect. One out of six problems found.
Repair. Okay. Test.
That's it. I don't know. These are not
exactly what I thought I would be
getting. So, this isn't super easy.
Like, I wanted to be able to say, "Hey,
you know, I would throw a kid in here
and tell him to go play in this game and
learn these concepts, but this is a bit
confusing." And now we have the AI
Explorer Academy that was created by
Opus. This is more of a little robot.
It's more of a third person sort of
vibe. And we have different rooms to go
into as well. I think this one I mean I
played with this one yesterday but this
one's a little bit more I don't know
it's simple. You can see token blocks.
This is how AI reads tokens. We come
over here and we can use this machine
which basically helps us drop in some
balls and we can choose the different
temperature. So the temperature changes
like how many the randomness I guess and
then if I drop in some balls you can see
that it's going to fall into the next
word like the cat's head on the mat or
the cat's head on the floor or the roof
or you know the other ways that these
things are predicted. Now, there is an
issue here where when you drop these
balls in, they kind of get stuck
sometimes. So, that would be a little
bit of a bug, but considering that this
wasn't the main game that was created
inside of this world, it's really not
too bad. Let's go into something else.
I'll go into the agent arena over here.
AI that works in a loop. We see what do
we have right here? Pick a mode on the
console. So, we can run one shot with no
loop or we can run an agent loop. Let's
run an agent loop and see what happens.
So, we can actually see the agent doing
things. It's thinking, it's checking.
It's thinking, it's checking, and it
needs to get to the end goal. So, it's
going to think, check until it's able to
find its way over here to the flag. So,
you can see that that was seven loops.
So, that's pretty cool. What if I reset
the rover and then just did run one shot
with no loop? It would just think and
act and it just goes straight towards
the goal, but it runs into the boxes all
the time. So, that's honestly a pretty
good little visualization. Anyways, I
think you guys get the point. Each of
these rooms has a different concept um
that has to do with AI automation. And
then there's a bit of a simulation or
some sort of game where you're able to
actually see what's going on. This one
looks like there's an actual like helper
shop. So, now we're getting into some
like business concepts where you open up
the shop. Next customer, next customer.
This one looks like it might be broken,
but anyways. Oh, nope. There comes the
customers. I was mistaken. Deal. Only
200 bucks. Wow. That is super cheap for
what it saves me. Okay, cool. So, that
is the world that Opus 5.5 created. Now,
this one is interesting. It took us an
hour and 44 minutes with Opus 5.5, which
makes sense. I mean, that was pretty
complex. $60 with Opus. Astro ran for 45
minutes and only took $12. So, this is
going to be an interesting one. I
ultimately the quality of what we got, I
liked Opus' better. And some of you guys
would say, okay, so Opus wins this one,
especially because you think about the
fact that we did a slashgoal prompt. So,
Opus fulfilled the goal better. But one
thing that I think is interesting to
think about is Astra here only took you
12 bucks. What if you iterated with
Astra, maybe shot off another prompt
with feedback, and you let it run until
it hit 60 bucks? Would Astra's output
for $60 been better than Claude Opus'
output here for 60 bucks? I would argue
yes. Now, of course, that takes into
account that we're able to literally
provide feedback, so it's getting more
tailored towards what we're looking for,
but I do think it's an interesting way
to think about it. So Astra was
obviously cheaper here and faster, but
if we're talking just the actual quality
that came back in it one/goal prompt,
then I would be giving this one to Opus
5.5. All right, so moving on to number
seven. I told it that I wanted to take a
trip from October 1st to October 30th. I
wanted all these sorts of things and I
told it to just make me a 3D immersive
itinerary um that looked like a world
that I could sort of like journey
through and see visually where I'm going
and I wanted to provide me all the links
that I needed in order to get around. So
here is Astros. It's called Atlas. We
can see that we're starting off here in
Chicago. We're getting a little bit of a
3D world here where I can click into the
next days and it will show me exactly
where I'm going. So, I would be going
over here all the way to what is that?
Iceland. And then we'd be coming back
over to the Netherlands in Amsterdam.
There's a World Summit AI. So, pretty
cool. Then we'd be going to San
Francisco for Tech Week. It looks like
we have all these other events going on
in here. San Francisco for about a week.
It looks like other places in
California, Yusede. We'd end up going to
Utah for Zion because I said national
parks. We'd also be able to hit some of
the other national parks in Utah. It
looks like Bryce Canyon. We'd go to
Vegas and then we'd come back home to
Chicago. Okay, pretty cool. Now, I'm
assuming all of these have things like
this one has some shuttle times for us.
This one has weather conditions or
conditions of the park. We've got um the
driving route right here that we could
open up, which is on Google Maps. We've
got some flights that we can look at on
Kayak. So, it looks like it's providing
all of the right links for us. So, this
would definitely make our life a lot
easier if we wanted to plan out this
trip. Okay, then here is Opus' version.
So, we have the same sort of thing on
the bottom. We can actually hit play and
just see this happen. I guess it will
sort of cycle through different days.
That's kind of cool. I like that
animation there. It's going to take us
to these different areas as you can see.
And all of these have links like you can
see. We have this boat tour which I can
go here to grab some tickets. We have
this sky lagoon which I can click on
here to get tickets there. Um, we have
some flight stuff. World Summit Day. So,
the itinerary is honestly pretty similar
as far as it finding these different AI
events as well as finding California
parks, Utah parks. It found all of this
stuff for us. Once again, GitHub
Universe and then we would be taking
this flight. Although, oh, there's the
the links to a Southwest flight right
here via Google Flights. So, I think
they both did a pretty solid job. It
would just be more of a matter now of
like, okay, which one do I like the
actual design better from? And what do
we think about the speed and cost? This
is kind of a cooler immersive 3D map, I
would say, but it loads pretty slow. So,
there's definitely some optimization we
could make there. But let's go ahead and
take a look at the performance. So,
pretty similar here. Opus was 29
minutes, Astra was 32 minutes, Opus was
1447, and Astra was $11. I honestly am
going to give the edge here to Astra. I
think that Astra's version is very
clean. It's got all the links right
here. They're both very good, but I
think that Astra's might just be a
little bit cleaner, especially when you
look at how some of their stuff was. So,
I'm going to give experiment number
seven to Astra 6. Okay. So, now what we
have is a codebased challenge. I
actually had Grock design a challenge
for me and then I had Grock look it over
with Fable 5.1 and GBD6 Soul. So, I just
kind of got a mixture of experts in
there and they designed this experiment.
And then what I did is I gave that
experiment to Opus and to Astra. These
are the results that we see which is
pretty interesting. Astra was way more
efficient on both speed and cost. And
then when I had multiple agents review
this again, they all sort of agreed on
this, which was the idea that they both
did really well here. They both passed
with 100 out of 100 score, except for
Fable did say that agent B got two
points deducted on one of these
experiments over here, which would have
given it a total of 98 out of 100, which
actually doesn't make perfect sense if
you actually look at these scores right
here because it got 61 out of 62 and 10
out of 12. But anyways, the conclusion
that I got was basically that both of
these agents with this sort of coding
task, very very good. Like very very
good agents. They both did a great job.
I still would feel more comfortable
having both agents run through and help
me repair and find bugs and things like
that. But ultimately, if you look at the
efficiency here, this is going to be a
clear win for Astra. It's not even
close. It was, you know, a fifth of the
time as well as half the cost. So this
one definitely goes to Astra. And I do
think so far this really aligns with the
way I'm feeling about in general Open
Eye versus Enthropic. Enthropic seems to
be way more creative. I feel like it
usually has better taste. And then
OpenAI is just like super pragmatic,
super logical, super reasonable. And if
you're giving it something very, very
specific, it's just going to execute
that for you pretty much the way you
want it. So that's kind of the way in
general I feel. But let's move on to
number nine. Okay, so number nine is
interesting. I wanted it to build me a
30-cond animated Instagram reel, just
telling the story of me. I wanted it to
think about what it knows about me, do
some research, and generate whatever it
wants in order to make this a real about
me. me. So, I just wanted to see what it
could do. And this is one of those where
it's very creative. So, I wanted to see
who would win here. My gut is telling me
that Opus is going to come through
better, but you never know. So, let's
give these both a watch. Here is Opus
5.5's version. 2 years ago, I was
building dashboards at Goldman Sachs
with zero coding background. My
automations followed rules, but they
couldn't think. So, I taught myself AI
agents and posted everything on YouTube.
Two months later, I quit. A small free
group became AI Automation Society, now
450,000 builders. The channel passed a
million subscribers. My book hit number
one. And we launched a certification.
I'm 24 and I'm just getting started.
That's pretty funny. It made a Pixar
style person. It has the shirt that I
wear in most my thumbnails. And it has I
don't know. This looks like maybe my
profile picture. I'm not exactly sure.
This is kind of funny. I mean, this is
all pretty accurate. I like the way it
did it. It also used my voice. It used
my 11 Labs voice clone. So, not too bad.
Let's go ahead and see what Astra gave
us.
>> Before a million subscribers, Nate Herk
had a webcam and a towel under his
keyboard. Fresh out of college, he moved
from Illinois to Salt Lake City. He
started learning AI, building things,
and sharing what worked. The videos were
rough. He kept showing up. Those
tutorials grew into the AI Automation
Society, a community learning alongside
him. And after all of that, he's still
learning, still building, still hitting
record.
Okay. Well, first of all, still hitting
record. I think that should have been
still hitting record, but this one
didn't choose to use my clone, my voice
clone. It also chose to make this sort
of more of like a claimation style. I'm
not exactly sure what you would call it,
but they chose different styles. They
also clearly used the same reference
image, that picture of me in that like
light blue shirt. It's interesting too
because Opus chose like to narrate in
first person whereas Asha chose to make
this like more of a biography. You know,
it's hard for me to choose a winner
here. I think that it's they both did
something interesting. I just wanted to
see what happened. But if we take a look
at this stuff now, we have an
interesting one. So Astra ran for 20
minutes. Opus ran for almost 50, but
Opus was cheaper at $8, whereas Astra
was $11. So in this sort of a scenario
where I don't care about speed, and I
more so would care about the cost and
the quality, I don't know. I think that
Opus' version, one of the other things
that I liked about Opus' version better
is that it had at the top like a
progress bar. You could see from
September 2024 all the way to today,
it's kind of like showing you where you
are on the journey. Whereas in Ash's
version, it was just like these
different chapters and it felt a little
bit hard to understand how it all linked
together. So, we'll give this one to
Opus, which is kind of what I thought
was going to happen based on previous
experiments with like video editing and
just creative direction in general. All
right, so this next one is one of my
favorite new benchmarks. It's the Canva
drawing one. You can see that I'm going
to give them this image and I say open
up Canva. Use browser use to draw this
picture as accurately as possible with
painting tools and not generating an
image. So, if we take a look here at
Astro's version, if I open up this
browser, I mean, this is awful. Like,
this is terrifying. This is scary. You
can see that it tried to put some
texture in my shirt, like the sort of
this waffle pattern. It tried to, you
know, it added the zippers on Adam
Sandler's shirt and things like that,
but the faces, this is nightmare fuel,
100%. I'm not sure what happened. In the
past when I've done this with Astra,
it's been incredible. Like you can see
it's highlighting the arm nice with like
shadows, the face. Like I think it's
trying to do a good job, but it just
completely butchers the facial elements.
And this is where I'm saying like I feel
like Asher has degraded because it used
to do this really good. Like when Ashra
dropped, there was tons of people doing
this on X and on LinkedIn and I was
doing it and I thought it was really
good. Like actually just for reference,
this is what it did for me earlier. Like
this was Astra's output when Astra first
dropped which I thought was really good.
If you look at the reference image and
here's another one that Astra built me
as well, which wasn't as good as the
first one, but this is clearly a better
technique than what we're seeing right
here for I I don't exactly know why. And
here, let's go to Fable's output. This
is really good. This is more like what
Ashra was giving me when this whole
thing started up. And based on the
reference image, you clearly see here
that Opus 5.5 wins. And it's not even
close at all. Like this looks I don't
know. It just looks like someone who
forgot to put their glasses on in the
morning. It's just a little bit blurry.
And when you think about the fact that
Opus 5.5 was cheaper for that output,
it's a no-brainer. Opus 5.5 is
definitely winning this one, which yeah,
I mean, I know a lot of these are
subjective. It's not exactly a
benchmark, but I think the whole point
of testing models is testing them on
your use cases, your knowledge work, the
way that you use AI. And I use AI a lot
for creative style work. So testing this
sort of stuff for me is very helpful to
understand what I'm working with. All
right, so number 11 is creating an
Instagram carousel. Now, I do have a
skill that helps us do this. So, they
were hopefully going to both use the
skill, but I shot them an X article or
an X tweet and said, "Hey, make me the
Instagram carousel." And let's see what
we get back from Claude. So, here is
Claude's output. Let me just make this a
little bit bigger. Here we have nearly
nine in 10 Americans call AI a threat.
Their number one fear is at losing
control. We have a picture. I think this
is the Terminator here. And as we go
through, we have a different stat with
images up top. We've got an actual quote
from some sort of poll. We have more
stats. And obviously this is going to be
formatted in a very specific way because
of the skill. Now I think this image
feels like it could have been lowered a
little bit. I feel like that could have
had some better verification. I think
this one too. Um this one as well. So
all of these images could have been I
guess positioned and sort of like
centered a little bit more. So that is
Opus's output. And then here is the
output we got from
Astra. And already I like it better
because it put the little Poly Market
logo which is the original tweet that we
sent in. We have a robot there. Nearly 8
in 10 Americans worry about AI escaping
human control. I think that might be a
better like opening caption as well. We
have the actual tweet which I do like
having that there. We have 79% concerned
with a little bit of an image. We have a
nice image there with a stat. Another
little stat. Another little poll. We've
got the same alien or not alien. We have
the same like robot astronaut image. So
I wish they did a different one there.
Keep approval on before AI sends. We
have a call to action. And then we have
a final picture. Overall, I think that I
like the taste that Astra used here.
Even though they were both given the
same thing, they were both using the
same skill. I think that Astra wins this
one based on its taste and its judgment
in what it actually turned into a
carousel. So, this one I am going to
give to Astra. And Ashra also came
through about half the time and um about
60% 70% of the cost. So, $10 compared to
almost $7. This one is going to go to
Astra. All right. So, this is the next
one. This is the site that I gave it.
This is my site for my book, Becoming I
Native. This isn't actually updated, so
I do need to update this. But I gave it
this site, and I wanted to see if it
made a new version of this for me, what
it would do, as well as if it might
update some of these numbers, which are
outdated. So, we'll see if either of the
agents were, I guess, like pragmatic
enough to go think about updating those
numbers. So, this is the one that Astra
gave us. We can see we have become AI
native. I hate this logo up in the top
left. Hate that. Make AI part of how you
work. We can explore the book or we can
buy on Amazon which does take us to the
actual book. We can see we have a little
bit of a dynamic book image right here.
The three M's number one Amazon
bestseller 850K 425. So it basically
treated the website as the source of
truth and it didn't think to fact check
any of that. So I don't love it but you
know we'll see if Opus did that as well.
The tools will change your approach can
last. This is a very very boring site.
It also just gives off like very cheaply
built. So I definitely don't love this
at all. Let's go ahead and see what we
got from Opus. Okay, I don't like this
on first glance. I mean, it's too I
don't know. It's like doomsday. It's not
the vibe I was going for. I mean, I
think it probably looked at the cover
and was like, "Oh, well, maybe it's like
kind of dark mode and, you know,
whatever." I like how up here, this
looks a little bit more branded than
just having AI. I mean, this is
definitely better. But as we scroll
through, we have the number one Amazon
bestseller. We have 4.4 out of five
stars. We have the pricing here, 35
ratings. We can get on Amazon. We can
read the first page. Okay, that's kind
of cool. It it puts the first page out
here. We have the three M's. It's taking
some actual pictures in there, the
method, the machine. It's showing you
the actual chapters as well. It's
showing us some of the frameworks in
here. So, I mean, this is overall it's
it's telling a better story. I mean,
look at the reviews, too. This is
definitely the better site. It just
needs some work on the design, but it is
100% a better experience than this,
which just feels like a oneshot prompt
to, you know, an AI model from 2 years
ago on Lovable or something like that.
This is definitely a better experience.
So, Opus is going to take this one as
well. Let's take a look at the pricing
here. Very, very similar. About 14
minutes for each. And Opus was a dollar
more expensive. So, this one is also
going to go once again to Opus 5.5,
which in general, I'm just very, very
impressed with this model. It is a very,
very good model. Okay, so after all
those experiments, we're sitting at GBT
Astra having won four of them and Opus
winning eight of them. So it's 8 to4
opus. Obviously a lot of that is
subjective I know but that's the way
that I am giving them my ranking based
on my use cases and my taste. So after
all of these 12 experiments opus 5.5 ran
for almost 11 hours. GBD6 Astra ran for
6 hours. Opus cost me $214 if this was
API billing and Astra would have cost me
$132. So Astra in general 45% faster and
38% cheaper which is very interesting
considering it is a 2.5x on the price
compared to Opus 5.5. So what that tells
me is Astra is a very very efficient
model but sometimes at least in these
experiments Opus was understanding what
I wanted a little bit better and it was
giving me more creativity and its
outputs were just a little bit more
aligned with what I want. And like I
said earlier in this video, I've felt
like for a while now that Opus and
Claude models feel like a wise old owl.
They feel like they have good judgment
and creativity and taste. And GBT models
just feel like they are a really good
obedient worker. They're going to get
the job done. They are going to like
they want you to give them a very
specific spec. They want you to tell
them exactly what you want and they'll
figure out how to get there. They're
very goal-oriented. But when you give
GBT models vagger goals, you might get
frustrated with what they're coming back
with because it just feels like they
weren't meant for those vague goals as
much as something like these claw models
were. Ultimately, what else I think is
that both of these models are so so good
when you look at the average task that
you're running, knowledge work or simple
like merges or building little apps or
dashboards. Both of these apps are going
to be so so good at giving you that
functionality. It's really about the way
that you talk to it on top of that and
the context that you add on top of that
to actually make it align with what you
want because I want things different
than you want it. You want things
different than your friend wants it. So,
it's like how do you actually
communicate on top of the sort of like
base fundamentals, the 70% plumbing that
everyone needs to set up in the same
way. On top of that, what's the 30% that
gets you there to where you actually are
like, damn, like I really like this
output. So, anyways guys, I hope that
you found this one insightful. I hope
you enjoyed you learned something new.
And if you did, please give it a like.
It helps me out a ton. And as always, I
appreciate you guys making it to the end
of the video and I'll see you on the
next one.